Supplemental Guide to the Collection of the Association for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women Southern Region II, 1984
University Archives
Supplemental Guide to the Collection of the Association for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women Southern Region II,1984
1984
Association for Intercollegiate Athletics For Women Southern Region II
Eastern Kentucky University Archives Richmond, Kentucky 40475-3102
Collection is open for research.
Container List
- Ethics and Eligibility Series
  The Ethics and Eligibility Series consists of two folders of correspondence materials (See Collection 83A5, Ethics and Eligibility, Correspondence Subseries.)
  - Correspondence
    - September 21, 1979 - November 29, 1979. (Box 1)
    - February 7, 1980 - April 14, 1981. (Box 1)
- Membership Series
  The Membership Series consists of two folders of materials containing a subseries:A. Applications Subseries (See Collection 83A5, Memberships, Applications Subseries) and B.List Subseries (See Collection Memberships, List Subseries.)
  - Applications Subseries Box 1 1981-82 (KY, NC, SC, TN, and VA).
  - List Subseries 1980-81
- National Championship Series
  The National Championship Series consists of one folder of materials of a miscellaneous nature pertaining to National Championships in 82. (See Collection 83A5, National Championship Series.)
  - General
    - National Championship Series (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1981-82. (Box 1)
- Publication Series
  The Publications Series is composed of various publications of AIAW and AIAW Region II. The publications are organized chronologically.
  - General
    - "Southern Region II Association for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women, Constitution" April 1, 1978. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Association for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women Competitive Division Structure Implementation Survey." Fall, 1978. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Association for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women Committees and Representatives Notebook." May l, 1981. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "National Association for Girl's and Women in Sport, Board of Directors Minutes." October 2, 1981. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Regional Representative Series
  The Regional Representative Series consists of one box of materials containing two subseries: A. Correspondence Subseries (see 83A5, Regional Representative, Correspondence Subseries and AIAW National Meetings, Reports, and Minutes Subseries).Important information on the dissolution of AIAW can be found in folder three of this subseries(April 13 - June 7, 1982).
  - Correspondence Subseries
    - June 2, 1975 - October 31, 1978. (Box 3)
    - February 12, 1979 - December 12, 1979. (Box 3)
    - January 15, 1980 - October 24, 1980. (Box 3)
    - January 1, 1981 - December 06, 1981. (Box 3)
    - January 20, 1983 - October 26, 1984. (Box 3)
  - AIAW National Meetings, Reports and Minutes Subseries
    - May 5 - 7, 1981. (Box 3)
    - October 13 - 16, 1981. (Box 3)
    - April 13 - June 7, 1982. (Box 3)
- Legal Series
  The Legal Series is composed of one box of materials and is divided into two subseries: A. Correspondence Subseries and B. Brief Subseries.
  The Correspondence Subseries consists of one folder in Box 14. The material is arranged chronologically and deals with correspondence of the case: Association for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women v. National Collegiate Athletic Association.
  The Brief Subseries consists of tile briefs of the aforementioned court case. The history of men's and women's athletics and the events and circumstances surrounding the court case of the AIAW. NCAA are detailed in these briefs.
  - Correspondence Subseries
    - October 9, 1981 - June 11, 1982. (Box 4)
  - Brief Subseries
    - 1981 - 1982 (Box 4)
- Financial Series
  The Financial Series consists of four subseries: A. Ledger Subseries. B. Invoide Subseries, C. Tournament Financial Reports Subseries, and D. Tax Exempt Status Subseries.
  The Ledger Subseries is one folder of three financial ledgers. Limited financial information about AIAW Region II in the years 1975, 1978-79, 1979-80, and 1980-81 is recorded in these ledgers.
  The Invoice Subseries is three folders of invoices. These invoices reflect the membership dues paid by AIAW Region II institutions in 1977 and 1978.
  The Tournament Financial Report Subseries is two folders of AIAW Region II Tournament Financial Reports for basketball in 1978, 1980, and 1981 and other regional sports tournaments in 1979 and 1980. The materials in this subseries supplements but may also duplicate materials in Collection 83A5, Regional Championship Series.
  The Tax Exempt Status Subseries contains Internal Revenue worksheets and correspondence for verification of the tax exempt status for AIAW Southern Region II, 1981.
  - Ledger Subseries
    - 1975, 1978-79, 1979-1980, 1980-81, 1981-82. (Box 5)
  - Invoice Subseries
    - 1977. (Box 5)
    - 1978 (Box 5)
    - Undated (Box 5)
  - Tournament Financial Report Subseries
    - 1979, 1980, 1982 (Box 5)
    - Basketball, 1978, 1980, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Tax Exempt Status Subseries
    - 1981 (Box 5)
  - Budget, Financial Statements
    - 1981-1983 (Box 5)
- Memorabilia Series
  The Memorabilia Series consists of two items: two tennis medals with the words"1st Place Doubles, 1979" engraved on the back and one plaque which belonged to BeckyHudson, AIAW Southern Region Representative, 1979-1981.
  - General
    - Tennis Medals (2), 1st Place Doubles, 1979. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - AIAW Plaque, Becky Hudson, AlAW Southern Region, 1979 - 1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Volleyball Medals (3), Silver (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Gymnastics Ribbons, Balance Beam; 1st Place - 4, 2nd Place - 4, 3rd Place - 4, 4th Place - 3, 5th Place - 2, 6th Place - 4 (Box 5, Folder 4)